hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Krakowski and on this podcast I
talk about how coaches trainers mentors
and thought leaders can scale their
businesses and make millions of dollars
online using online direct response
marketing Facebook ads virtual events
and offers that attract the right
clients that they're looking for now I
want to talk about market research today
market research is
one of the most important things that
you must do in your coaching business if
you want to be successful you need to
understand who you're actually marketing
to and if you don't have experience
working with 100 to 200 people that
you're coaching already it can be
difficult to know how can I actually
find these clients and so in today's
episode we're going to go over the
methods that we use for market research
what I do is I like to implement into
the entire process market research from
stage one a big mistake that a lot of
coaches make they spend a lot of time
doing market research before they're
actually building their coaching
business that's a big problem another
mistake that coaches make is that they
try to create a bunch of content before
doing market research another big
problem and so the reason behind this is
because of how people see the coaching
industry and what they think they should
do and what I want to bring to you is my
experience in over 20 years work in this
industry seeing what works
and what doesn't and what works the best
is a simultaneous
doing market research along with testing
and experimenting to see what the
marketplace responds to and so the first
thing that I want you to understand is
that initially especially if you don't
have hundreds of clients already it's
it's a normal thing that you're not
going to just suddenly make a million
dollars by launching a course or a
coaching program so understand that
understand that that is part of the
process and if that's not okay with you
you may want to consider going and
getting a job and not doing the coaching
business because you you have to operate
inside of the realm of reality in the
realm of what actually works and market
research is a big part of that process
now market research does cost money but
the method that we use
allows you to do it in a way that isn't
going to actually be a net negative to
your bank account a lot of people
believe that it takes a massive amount
of Deep Pockets to be able to be
successful to research to learn what
they need to do to get more clients and
that's simply not true the old ways of
doing stuff sure maybe now we have new
tools with artificial intelligence that
allows us to save a lot of time in our
market research process so the first
step that I always start with is you
want to decide on what is a topic or
Niche that you can coach on and what I
would love to do is I'm actually going
to take three different resources here
we're going to go into into chat GPT
we're going to go into uh bing and we're
also going to go into Bard okay so these
are three different AI resources
um that operate similarly to each other
but they're not exactly the same and so
we're gonna we're gonna ask these
questions individually of each of these
watch this if you're watching on on
YouTube you can actually see it visually
as I'm doing this okay so
Bard we're gonna ask Bard what are 100
possible niches or topics that people
could start
a coaching business
course business
mentorship company or become a thought
leader
or trainer around and make a significant
income doing so if they do
yeah doing so there we go
now we're going to ask these three
different AIS this question right here
okay let's try this now
let's try chat GPT
and then we're gonna go into
um
chat in
in bing right here and we're gonna go
uh balanced right there all right and so
all three of these AIS are going to come
up with a few niches business coaching
career coaching life coaching
mindset coaching Financial coaching
Health coaching Fitness coaching
relationship coaching parenting
spiritual travel Tech fashion grooming
etiquette public speaking sales
negotiation leadership creativity
productivity Stress Management
sleep coaching weight loss coaching pain
management addiction mental health
chronic illness disability end of life
so these are a few ideas right here in
bard
let's see Bing gave us career coaching
Fitness spiritual parenting family oh
here's here's a great list from chat gbt
right here personal development coaching
business startup Consulting career
coaching
so you see the ideas right here you know
we got videography coaching foreign
language coaching
acting coaching magic coaching Airbnb
rental success coaching tiny house
living coaching Craft brewery training
okay so these are all ideas that you
could use and honestly you can use chat
gbt to come up with and find a couple of
different ideas that you like or are
interested in so what I tell people is
pick one or two and you can usually
combine those into some kind of a
coaching now the next thing that you
want to do is once you find what you
actually want to do let's say that
you're going to do 3D printing
coaching
generate I'll do what's called sub
niches generate 27 niches around
3D printing coaching
let's see let's see what bard
also says to this
the bod
these are different forms of AI but
we're going to get slightly different
researches 3D printing for beginners for
designers for engineers for hobbyists
for health care for Pat so the idea is
you want to pick something that you
actually have experience around first
off
something that that you know how to do
and then chat gbt can help you come up
with some different ways to apply this
and actually do it let's do in education
okay
so those are some like great ideas that
you could start with
similar here you know
kind of like that these AI tools will
allow you to come up with some great
ideas that you could use to jog your
memory and come up with ideas of where
to start with that now what I want to
look at is I want to look at
um on Amazon
if I go to amazon.com
and I look at 3D printing
for
teachers
you're going to see a number of
different books that are written 3D
printing Made Easy classroom guide to 3D
printing 3D printing for dummies
okay
designed for 3D printing
here we go so what I'll look at is these
books right here they have descriptions
and these are generally the questions
that people are going to be asking
initially when they want to learn how to
do something like this you'll notice
that these are books that are being sold
that that have been purchased by people
and that's why they're on Amazon and
they're pulling up on here so what I'll
do is I'm going to paste
just some of these book descriptions
into chat GPT
I'm just going to copy and paste this
right into here
okay
and let's leave that one out
and I'm just going to type that in
seems you're describing a range of
educational resources
yep each of these is a unique
perspective on 3D printing whether
you're a hobbyist or something you
wanted to create this 3D printing books
can help you with that okay so now let's
take a look at how do you translate this
into a coaching business well you have
to actually sell it to people and you
have to actually see what the market
responds to and this is where the market
research aspect comes into it our first
initial stage of market research is we
ask chat GPT these certain questions
okay
we're able to look at Amazon what is
Amazon saying about these let's say you
generate
um 20 search
terms for answer the public
.com that might pull up some interesting
info about this industry
for my market research around 3D
Printing and by the way you can ask chat
gbt as well
you know what are some other areas to
look into for market research around 3D
printing
that I should explore if I'm going to
sell coaching
okay analyze different types of
customers competitive analysis different
pricing models industry trends
skills gaps where where are potential
customers struggling the most see so
chat gbt can give you ideas as to how to
come up with what you're looking for for
your market research already we know
more about
selling coaching to to 3D printing than
anything else in fact we can also ask
can you answer these questions for me
about market research
uh provide a list of questions uh let's
see
take the 10
items above
and give me your input about the
industry
the 3D printing industry spans multiple
sectors hobbyists and makers educational
institutes such as stem education and
entrepreneurs so that's really where
people are going to want to get into it
is for jobs competitive analysis pricing
models pricing is either on courses
workshops or one-on-one coaching skills
gaps it involves a learning curve users
often struggling with mastering design
software troubleshooting printing issues
and understanding material properties so
that's great right there so now let's do
this
write me a sales letter for a free
webinar training about the above for a
program for 3D printing related to and
then we're going to put the skills gaps
right in here
are you an aspiring 3D printing
Enthusiast educator have you ever felt
overwhelmed by the complexity of 3D
software design
demystifying 3D software design
troubleshooting issues understanding
materials so right now automatically we
have an offer right here now you might
be saying well I don't know if this
Market is going to respond to this so
this is where part of our market
research comes in you can take some of
this and pull this into
answerthepublic.com
to get some ideas as to
what this Market actually wants
you can see what people are searching
for what they're saying what interests
of people actually are related to this
and this is a great way to to do some
research because what this does is you
can find some of the the outputs that it
gives you
such as how does 3D printing work let's
say that that's something that people
are searching for
and then we can look how does 3D
printing work with metal okay and so
then we can find
you know who are the who's teaching
about Metal that's out here we got Mark
forged
so what you're looking at is you're
looking at
who else is out here serving or
organizing different Industries who's
out here serving different
um hi everyone stuff that people is
actually looking for
who's teaching other people one about
this topic hi and welcome
and how are they running their business
what are they teaching people about
specifically the next video in our
series
okay
now chat GPT has a great function where
we could actually take this
right here
and we can open up
with a plug-in
you can use a plug-in
called Vox script and I could say
generate 20 possible ideas for a
coaching business based on this video
and I can paste the YouTube video right
in here and it's going to give me some
ideas based on the transcript of this
video it's actually going to download
the transcript right here
and it's going to split it up into three
different chunks and be able to actually
look at what is being talked about in
the video to create some great ideas for
coaching based off of what's actually
being shared in the video okay SLS 3D
printing Basics course Advanced 3D
printing techniques so you could take
videos off of YouTube have chat gbt
analyze them and help you come up with
your market research initially
so that's your initial stage of your
market research is to take a look at
what YouTube videos are out there
what is pulling up on
answerthepublic.com what are people
asking for on here
that they want to learn
and what books are on Amazon and then
bring all of that together
into chat GPT
let's say that we're going to be doing
SLS 3D printing
Basics let's go right here we have this
one right here this basic course right
here
so what you would want to do and this is
where most people get stuck
is they're looking for certainty and a
guarantee that this is going to be
profitable for them
and unfortunately that's not possible
without actually testing and seeing what
your Market will respond to we've taken
a look at what are some of the top
pieces of content that pull up when
we're searching certain things
to find great pieces of content that are
out there and you can even search
YouTube what are some YouTube
search
terms for this Market
some YouTube Searcher 3D printing
for beginners
okay so now we can see the edge of tech
Austin Hartley
in this video we're turning this basic
different people teaching he's teaching
mechanical engineering 3D printing this
is what his whole business is so we're
able to look at
what is he teaching
what is this all about we can pull this
into chat GPT right here
have it use that same plugin
uh pull out an outline for a course
based on this video
see so you can literally find videos
that are on YouTube and then have it
analyze the transcript this is the Vox
script plugin in chat GPT plus and it's
going to analyze the transcript and then
give you an output from the transcript
as to what it thinks would be a great
idea for you to use for your own courses
and training and coaching watch this
this is like magic
it's it's it's it's splitting it into
chunks and then it analyzes each chunk
based on my question and then brings
that all together
it's really intuitive how it works
and these plug-in functions are really
great in chat GPT all right here it is
based on the transcript here's a
potential outline for a course setting
up your printer
understanding materials
creating 3D printer files
where to buy them
you know thingyverse I didn't even I
I've heard of thingyverse but look at
this you could literally download
fully created
objects that then you can print out at
home
right here on this website on
thingiverse
you know I mean some of that's
definitely kind of scary looking but
so as a 3D printer right here you're
able to go through and you're able to to
we were able to reverse engineer a video
and generate an outline for a course
that you could create on this topic
and then take your own knowledge bring
it into all of this and combine that
together
okay
here's an outline for a course
now I have some chat GPT prompts that
are actually over at my website if you
go to jeremyarkowski.com I have my free
chat GPT prompt download I I would
encourage you to go check this out it's
a
it's a document that has some really
great prompts for marketing in it
and for doing market research
and so if I go down here
and I pull up one of my favorite prompts
that we use all the time this is what
identifies a lot of the the main reasons
why people actually buy from us and it's
taken from the book by Dan Kennedy The
Ultimate Sales letter this is one of the
best books that you can read on sales
and marketing again you might be saying
Jeremiah I'm just in the market research
stage I'm not looking to sell anything
understand
that
this is how you get in front of the
right people and actually understanding
these questions is key to being able to
do your market research you want to be
able to answer what keeps somebody who
is looking to learn 3D printing up at
night it bothers them
what are they afraid of what's a 3D
printer afraid of what are they upset
about what are they frustrated about
what trends are occurring what do they
desire what's their own language who's
selling similar products
and so these questions are able to
actually answer those for us right here
and we're gonna have it list this out
somebody who's struggling to set up
their 3D printer
let me actually pull up Dan Kennedy
smart
Market questions 10 questions
we're gonna have it answer these
questions as well
answer these questions
about this market so we're able to do a
lot of the market research initially
whoops I didn't have the screen up here
I typed in Dan Kennedy's smart Market
questions from The Ultimate Sales letter
found somebody who basically wrote them
down right here
um and so I have all 10 of them right
there
so we're going to have it actually
answer these questions about the market
so we typed in the pain points the
struggle all of that
um I'm actually copy this down here
oh I don't have the
it's not edit available
so what keeps them up at night they're
concerned that their 3D printing will
fail they fear the possibility that
their printer will be damaged
they're frustrated with manufacturers
not providing comprehensive easy to
understand guides
this is great
all right so now what I'm going to do
is
I'm gonna also have an answer some of
these questions to really dive deeper
into what this client wants
to understand their pain points even
more key setbacks and challenges
um
their desired result is to create 3D
prints reliably and confidently to have
full control over their designs
um
they want to know that you can help
people accomplish these things
they want you to be able to help
solve a specific problem for them you
know tired of failing things like that
so these are some great ideas to come up
with that market research and then what
we do is we take this
and we're able to have it
write a sales letter for us are you
tired of wrestling with your 3D printer
trying to figure out why your prints are
coming out right fed up with countless
hours tweaking settings but still ending
up with a bird's nest of plastic instead
of meticulously designed masterpieces so
here's where the this is where the
rubber meets the road with actually
creating
um
doing the market research and if you're
wondering where you can find those
prompts they're over here it's just
right over at jeremyarkowski.com forward
slash chat GPT you can download that
document right here with some of those
copy and paste prompts that really go
into detail right here that we're going
over okay
what you want to do is you want to
actually put yourself out there
so that your target market that you're
trying to reach
[Music]
is going to respond to you
and you're able to have a conversation
with them now I don't recommend doing
this with one-on-one calls with people
for coaching I recommend doing this in a
group setting where you host a live Zoom
event where you do training and you
answer questions during the event and
you even maybe provide a backstage pass
access for seven to twenty seven dollars
where people can ask you questions I
host virtual events all the time where I
teach people about starting a coaching
business and then people can ask me
questions and a lot of what I'm teaching
is very similar to what I'm showing you
in this training video right here okay
and so very simply put
as part of your market research what you
want to do
is you want to attract who's actually
looking for these things
and you want to generate feedback from
those people to where they tell you what
they actually want and this is what most
people
don't do they they do everything that I
just showed you and then fall flat at
this stage to where they actually have
to interact with real human beings and
actually ask real people what they want
what they're struggling with and learn
from people what their desires are and
then what you want to do is you want to
take that feedback from people I have a
document of feedback from people and I
transcribe all of the meetings all the Q
a sessions that I do and I filter them
down with AI to extract what are the
actual desires that people want in their
own words okay so what I do is I start
with a very basic offer where I'm going
to create a very simple landing page
where people can sign up and register
this would be a simple landing page like
this
um this is an event that we're that
we're hosting here coming up starting
your six figure group coaching business
from scratch with AI
and this is where I'm hosting this on
zoom on Saturday June 17th
and I have when people register it's
free but after on the next page after
they register they have an opportunity
to to actually upgrade
and get access to the recordings as well
as a private Zoom room with me where
they can ask questions in Q a and this
is the only place that I provide q a is
they have to purchase for seven bucks I
mean it's not a lot but they had to
purchase for seven bucks the bonus
package to be able to get access to that
okay
and so I'm making an invitation to my
target market to connect with me
and the reason I'm doing this is to
gather the data that I need of who is
most likely to become a customer so as
part of our market research you actually
want to run an event
to where you're connecting with your
Market to see how do they respond what
do they respond to what words do they
respond to
and then you can tweak and adjust that
language and that will start to attract
more paid clients to you and that's how
we get a 20 to 30 times return on our
investment on a lot of our offers we
just ran an offer recently with my mom
that got
um
it brought in over three hundred and
sixty thousand dollars in sales
uh off of a ten thousand dollar ad spend
right here all about mastering stock
market strategies and multiplying their
daily earnings very simple very easy
turned into clients turned into
customers and it was very effective it
was a very effective way of getting
people to become a customer to become a
client in her business okay
and so virtual events is actually the
best way of getting clients into your
business but it's also the best way to
do that initial market research because
you're getting people in front of you
you're testing what you did with chat
GPT you're testing it out to see is this
going to work is this resonating with
people is this going to produce a result
and then what you do is you take the
results of that you analyze it and
you're able to optimize it and that
turns into a profitable coaching
business that's what I coach people on
that's what our YouTube channel is for
that's what our podcast is for us to
help you if you're a coach a mentor or a
trainer how to do the market research to
find what are the best topics that
people want how do you laser in your
message so that it attracts the people
who are most likely to get results with
you and spend the most amount of money
with you and that's important you want
to attract the people that are willing
to spend the most amount of money with
you as well as are also going to get
results so then you have case studies
and you're able to generate these case
studies and then that becomes like fuel
on the fire and your business will just
start to grow because of the success
that you're producing in your client's
life okay and so that's exactly what we
do is we start we go through the process
that I've just shown you in the last 30
minutes
and that's how anybody can start a
coaching business and do the market
research that they need to be successful
very simply very easily you don't have
to struggle you don't have to spend a
lot of time or energy or money doing
this and you can feel very confident in
the results all right
listen if this has helped you share this
with somebody else subscribe to our
YouTube channel subscribe to the podcast
and make sure to join us for one of our
live events that we're hosting you know
spend some time with me in a zoom room
where I'm going to be teaching this and
then you can ask me questions go head on
over to my website at
jeremykorkowski.com check out some of
the different offerings that we have and
as well I would encourage you to join
the waiting list for our group coaching
program the client growth accelerator
over at jeremiahkrakowski.com this is a
group program where I'm coaching people
every single week to help them grow in
their business to make more money and to
live the life that they've always wanted
I'd love to have you in there as well
all right we'll talk soon have a good
one